

Art Teacher markamos1991@yahoo.co.uk 07904976866

Manchester, United Kingdom

Mark Amos

Profile

Passionate, experienced, professional, and enthusiastic art teacher, with over 7 years of experience teaching a range of age groups internationally and in the U.K. I have experience teaching to A-level, GCSE, and Cambridge technical curriculums.

Employment History

Teacher of Art and Graphics at Aquinas Sixth Form College, Manchester

06/2022-Present

Taught upper and lower sixth students A level art and graphics to the AQA curriculum, in which I planned and assessed student work to the high standards of the college. Group tutor for lower sixth students in which I was responsible for student welfare and attendance alongside pastoral care. Rugby enrichment responsibility, arrange training and games and organising transport alongside coaching.

Teacher of Photography and Graphics at Oldham Sixth Form College, Oldham, Manchester

08/2021-06/2022

In this role I taught a range of photography, textiles (design component), graphic design, and mandarin Chinese at GCSE, AS, and A level. My role includes include, planning, assessing, and tracking of students. Additionally, ensuring the welfare and safeguarding of all students with the use of pastoral management systems. I am exposed to a wide range of students and utilize a variety of teaching and learning techniques to cater to the students' needs.

Art and Graphics Trainee Teacher at Aquinas Sixth Form College, Manchester

08/2020-07/2021

I have gained valuable experience working both remotely and on campus in the college's art and design department, teaching Art and Graphics. Whilst on placement I gained an understanding of online systems used to monitor student progress and engagement, furthermore I learned how to address safeguarding concerns and behavioral issues correctly. Besides my in-department experience during my placement at Aquinas, I was given the opportunity to run a virtual enrichment course teaching basic Mandarin Chinese.

Links

Personal Artwork Portfolio

Skills

Adobe Creative Suite
Mandarin Chinese
Google Classroom
Photography
Traditional Art Processes
3D Printing - Maintenance and Use
Web Coding - HTML, CSS, Javascript

Hobbies

I am a keen sportsperson and enjoy to live an active lifestyle, I enjoy running and swimming and enter running events each year. I am passionate about design and like to experiment with a range of design processes, I have darkroom experience and enjoy digital and traditional photography, alongside creating digital artwork through Adobe programmes and Procreate. I am a keen printmaker and enjoy relief printing and screenprinting. I like to challenge myself and I am currently gaining skills in web development and coding on a 16 week trainign bootcamp. I also love listening to music and can't go far without my wireless headphones. I hope to work in the UAE to further enrich my experiences of travel, languages and cultures.

References

Adam Smith from Oldham Sixth Form College

Classroom ESL Teacher at Science and Technology Foreign Language, Suzhou

08/2017-06/2019

Working in a classroom space alongside students throughout the day allowed me to understand how students work and behave, not only during class time but also in their free time. This in turn has grown my interpersonal skills with students and a strong understanding of how to build respect between different types of learners. Furthermore, whilst holding this position, I was directly communicating with students' parents and guardians on a regular basis. Due to this I have gained invaluable skills and methods to deal with a variety of issues and pressures. Leading me to be able to combine the goals and expectations of my employers, the students, the parents, and mine.

Classroom teacher/Foreign head teacher at Suzhou Foreign Language School Zhuyuan Kindergarten, Suzhou

08/2016-06/2017

In this position I have enriched my ability in engaging with young learners and working alongside Chinese staff. I have gained skills in classroom management and interpersonal skills with different types of learners. Here I also held the foreign head teacher role, in which I was required to liaise between Chinese management and the other foreign teachers within the department. I developed organisation skills from preparing events for holidays and special activities. Furthermore, my management of staff has grown, and I can handle issues with colleagues efficiently.

Language Assistant - British Council at Zhenhua Middle School, Suzhou

08/2014-06/2015

I developed in many areas of teaching, such as classroom management, delivering instructions, discipline and making learning as enjoyable as possible for the students. During my time working here I was required to teach a total of 800 students on a weekly basis, creating my own lesson plans and setting mid-term and end of term speaking exams. I developed a passion for teaching and found it extremely rewarding.

Education

PGCE 14 +, University of Bolton, Manchester

08/2020-06/2021

Graduated with Distinction Merit

BaHons Communication Design, University of Huddersfield, Huddersfield

08/2011-05/2014

ash@osfc.ac.uk N/A

Lauren Walton from Aquinas Sixth Form College

Lauren.walton@aquinas.ac.uk

Art Foundation, Stockport College

08/2010-06/2011

A level, Cheadle and Marple Sixth Form College

08/2008-06/2010

Art and Design A Level

Physical Education A level

Biology A level

NVQ Level 1 Sports coaching

GCSE, Marple Hall School

08/2003-06/2008

11 GCSE'S grades A-B

Extra-curricular activities

Rugby Enrichment at Aquinas Sixth Form College, Manchester

06/2022-Present

I have been in charge of the Sixth Form Rugby Union Team, I have arranged and held regular training sessions. I have arranged fixtures and entered tournaments with success - finishing second in the North West AOC rugby 7s tournament in November 22.

Mandarin Enrichment at Aquinas College/ Oldham Sixth form, Manchester

01/2020-04/2022

I organised and planned beginners mandarin Chinese lessons for students at both colleges. I planned an 8 week course in which students gained a basic understanding of writing systems, conversations, and cultural references.